Xiang.
向警官
Why am I here?
我怎么在这儿
A middle-aged woman noticed
是个中年妇女送你来的
you unconscious by the roadside
说你晕倒在路旁
treated you with the gunshot wound,
被他们发现了
and then brought you here.
还帮你处理了枪伤
Luckily,
幸亏你小子命大
it wasn't serious.
没伤到要害
You need more rest.
多躺几天就行了
Tianxiang!
哥
Qinqin!
勤芹
Finally!
姐 你可算回来了
Mr. Xiang is in Dad's room.
向警官在爸房间呢
He's injured.
受伤了
Dad.
爸爸
How are you?
你伤到哪儿了
I'm okay,
我没事儿
just got shot.
就是中了一枪
Have you seen Chen Hao?
你看到陈浩了吗
Where is he?
他在哪儿
He...
队长
probably not in Shanghai.
现在应该不在上海了
Mr. Qiao?
是乔先生吗
Yes.
我是
The Captain is in the car.
队长在车里面
Quick.
快
Careful.
轻一点
Easy.
轻点儿
Leave the rest to us.
剩下的事情交给我们
Mr. Qiao.
乔先生
Although we haven't met before,
之前我们虽然没有见过
Ms. Shi told me
但石小姐告诉过我
you can save the Captain.
你能救队长
Please
我求求你
make sure
答应我
to help him survive.
一定要救活队长
Don't worry.
放心
Go back now.
快回去吧
Newspaper!
看报 看报
Hot off the press!
新到的报纸
Deputy Security Director
公安局副局长
involved in munitions smuggling to Japan!
向日走私军需品
All documents
通行证 货单
exposed!
一并曝光
Unmissable!
大家快来买呀
Come here!
刚到的报纸
One, please.
给我来一份
One for me, too.
我要一份
News!
看报 看报
Hot off the press!
刚到的报纸
Deputy Security Director
公安局副局长
involved in munitions smuggling to Japan!
向日走私军需品
All documents
通行证 货单
exposed!
一并曝光
I'm Peng Ganwen, a reporter
我是《申报》记者
from Shen Bao.
彭甘文
I'm here to accuse
我要控告
the Deputy Security Director
公安局副局长谭施远
of colluding with QX JV Corp
勾结七祥国货联营公司
to smuggle munitions to Japan,
向日本走私军需品
and the work of Nakamura Naoki
控告弘济善堂的老板
as the owner
里见直树
of Hongji Benevolent Society
以做慈善为名
for his activities as a spy
其实受日本陆军省指派
for the Japanese Army Ministry.
行间谍之实
The National Government
东北沦陷
has repeatedly conceded,
华北事变
and officials have provided shelter
是南京政府的步步退让
for smuggling and tax evasion.
才让日本得寸进尺
Military discipline and forces
官员包烟庇赌
have thus been undermined.
走私漏税
All has enabled Japan to be lawless
以至军队军纪废弛
in North and Northeast China.
作战不力
Someone even shamelessly
更有人在大发国难财
served as a backup and profited greatly
甚至不耻为敌人输血
from it.
递子弹
The National Government
我们要求国民政府
must thoroughly investigate
彻查走私线
this smuggling route,
彻查为这条走私线
all officials who provided
提供免检通行证
inspection free passes
出港证的所有官员
and exit permits for this route,
更要求彻查背后的
as well as the Corp behind!
七祥国货联营公司
This is the recording
这是昨天在上海
of yesterday's rally in Shanghai.
那场集会的录音
Both
当天
the pass and the waybill
晚报就把通行证
were exposed the very evening,
和货单登出来了
and appeared
今天
in 5 morning papers
至少上了
in Shanghai and Nanjing today.
上海和南京五家的早报
Tan Shiyuan promised
虽然谭副局长答应过
to take full responsibility
该顶的罪名
for the charges.
他会一个不少顶下来
But there
但这件事
must also be someone
我们公司内部
within the company
也必须要有人
to take the blame.
来承担责任
I can.
我可以承担全部的责任
But listen,
但是今天
Family Hua
我也要告诉各位
will never
我们华家
be ousted
绝不会
from this table.
从这张桌子上出局
Not ever.
永远不会
Now
各位
if you'll excuse me.
先告辞了
We've known each other
认识这么久
for a long time.
我们第一次
This is our first meeting as comrades.
以同志的身份见面
Hello, Xiang Yuansheng.
你好 向远生同志
Under pressure,
江海关迫于压力
the Shinei Maru has been detained.
已经扣留了新荣丸号
Hongji Benevolent Society was closed.
弘济善堂被查封
Nakamura Naoki
里见直树
has been sent back to Japan.
也被遣回了日本
The waves created by this rally
这场集会掀起的声浪
were bigger than anticipated.
比我们想象中要大
Today, not just in Shanghai and Peking
今天除了上海 北平
masses in Nanjing
还有南京
also flooded the streets
有大量的群众涌上街头
demanding the release
他们要求释放
of the NSO's "Seven Gentlemen"
救国会七君子
and an end
也要停止
to the persecution of patriots.
对爱国人士的迫害
The
看来
power to resist
我们全国上下
Japanese aggression
抗日的力量
seems to be growing stronger.
越来越强大了
The higher-ups
组织对你
have greatly appreciated
还有陈浩 季太太
the efforts made
做出的努力
by you, Chen Hao, and Mrs. Ji.
给出了极大的肯定
You are
你们才是
the true unsung heroes.
背后的无名英雄
Still no word from Chen Hao?
还是没有陈浩的消息吗
Jianshi
我现在暂时
is temporarily out of touch.
联系不上老乔
But Chen Hao
但是陈浩说过
always says he's lucky.
他是一个运气好的人
We expect to hear good news soon.
我们会等到好消息的
I've never doubted that.
我从来没有怀疑过这点
Oh, yes.
对了
I have
今天
a new comrade
我还要给你介绍
to introduce to you.
一位新同志
Hi, Xiang Yuansheng,
向远生同志
Nice to meet you.
很高兴认识你
No need for more info, right?
这就不用我多介绍了吧
Shouldn't we
新同志见面
shake hands first?
不应该先握个手吗
When did you...
你什么时候
It's the Captain
是队长向石小姐
who proposed to Ms. Shi.
提出的申请
After his proposal,
陈浩向我提出申请之后
I reported it to the organization.
我就向组织汇报了
The application
组织已经同意了
has been approved.
珉敏的入党申请
No need to thank me.
不用感谢我
Surprised?
是不是很意外
Now we're comrades,
以后我们就是同志了
and I'll work hard.
我会好好努力的
Maybe
说不定
I'll be leading you one day.
以后我还能领导你呢
Mrs. Ji
季太太
was originally named Lanxin,
本来的名字叫陶兰心
meaning pure heart and personality.
兰心蕙质的兰心
She studied surgery
大学是在
at St. John's University School of Medicine
圣约翰医学院学的外科
and interned at Tongren Hospital.
后来去了同仁医院实习
She's the best
她是他们那一批
performing intern among those doctors.
最好的外科实习医生
Her husband
她和她的先生
is her classmate from university.
是大学同窗
They married after graduation
毕业之后就结了婚
and joined
后来又一起
the Communist Party together,
加入了共产党
immersing in a strong relationship.
他们的感情一直很好
They had a child
之前有过一个孩子
but sadly died young.
但很早的时候夭折了
In 1931,
民国二十年
they joined
夫妇二人
a medical team
一起加入了
heading to Northeast China.
赴东北抗日的医疗队
Her husband
她的先生
died at a battlefield
在战地救援的时候
rescue.
牺牲了
Then, she returned
后来季太太一个人
to Shanghai alone,
回到上海
and followed an order
组织安排她
to join in Mr. Deng's team.
进入了邓先生的小组
Publicly,
公开的身份
she's the owner of Zijin Tailor Shop.
是子衿裁缝铺的老板
But she's actually responsible
她在组里的任务
for resettling
是负责中转
new comrades in Shanghai
安排来上海的新同志
and transferring those at risk of exposure.
转移有暴露危险的同志
From that day,
从那天起
she became known as Mrs. Ji.
她就成了季太太
How long have you
你和季太太
known her?
认识多久了
Five years.
五年
When I first arrived
我记得我刚从莫斯科
in Shanghai from Moscow,
到上海的时候
I was a complete stranger.
人生地不熟
It's pouring rain
那天的上海
the day I arrived.
下着大雨
She picked me up at the train station.
是她到火车站来接的我
Mrs. Ji is to you
季太太之于你
as Mr. Deng is to me.
就像邓先生之于我
Although their lives
虽然他们的生命
were ended by the enemy's gunfire,
在敌人枪响后戛然而止
I believe
但我相信
they never had any regrets.
他们从未后悔过
They are forever immortal.
他们永垂不朽
Their ideals
他们的理想
are ours.
就是我们的理想
No matter how long it takes,
无论多久
they
理想
will eventually be realized.
终会实现
Coming!
来了 来了 来了
Hongfa!
鸿发
How's the fish?
鸿发 鱼怎么样了
Coming!
来了来了
Hurry up!
快快快
Why this?
怎么会是先放这个呀
Don't you need it first?
炒菜不得先炝锅吗
We always start
我们炒都是先放芹菜
with celery.
不放这个
During these years
怎么在四所
at the Fourth Station,
炒了这么多年菜
I've never seen anyone cook in this order.
头一次见到你这顺序
It's
骆叔
true.
这确实是
Our Chief has been cooking
我们所长这做饭时间呢
for long,
确实够长
his food really isn't good.
但确实难吃
It's awful.
太难吃了
I cook for you,
我还给你们做饭
and this is how
就养着你们
you repay me!
这些个白眼狼
My bad!
错了错了错了
Alright, eggs are ready!
好了好了 我鸡蛋好了
Coming!
鸡蛋好了
Move the knife!
你拿刀
We're about to eat.
别着急啊 马上开饭
When are you planning to leave?
你准备什么时候走啊
In a day or two.
就这两天了
Have you packed everything?
东西都收拾好了吗
Not much.
也没多少东西
Almost done.
收差不多了
Then...
那
Minmin!
珉敏
Come help me with the dishes!
进来帮我端下菜
When can we eat?
什么时候弄完啊
We're all waiting.
都等你这鱼
Stop nagging.
那你来
I'll do it.
我来
Pound the garlic!
你捣蒜 你捣蒜
No problem.
我捣蒜 来
Wait,
你等等等
you're so slow!
这么慢呢你
Look at this.
你看我这
You scrape it yourself.
你自己刮 来 你刮
No, I'm scared.
我不 我害怕
I'll do it then.
你不 我来吧
Clumsy!
笨劲儿
Here, I got it.
来 我来我来
I'll do it.
我来 我来
Can you not...
你能别
Wait a second.
等一等
Wait...
等 等 等
Is this you or Minmin?
这个是你还是珉敏姐
Definitely me.
那当然是我了
Can't recognize.
长得不像啊
I'm getting prettier,
女大十八变
right?
越变越漂亮吧
Guess who this is?
你猜这是谁
You, maybe?
这不会也是你吧
Must be Minmin!
这肯定是我姐
How ugly!
长这么丑
After born,
我跟你说
she's always
刚出生的时候
mistaken for a boy.
都以为是个男孩子呢
Don't ever tell her that.
千万不能跟她说啊
It's a deal.
好 我不跟她说
Dinner time!
来来来 吃饭了
Over here!
吃饭了
Tianxiang, come!
天祥 来
The fish is really good.
你这鱼做得真不错
Chopsticks!
拿筷子 拿筷子
Put it in the middle.
来来来 放中间放中间
Have a sit!
赶紧坐 赶紧坐
Hurry up.
所长 坐坐坐
Chief, please.
所长 坐 快
The rice
来来来
with veggies!
菜泡饭来了
This wine...
这酒
Where's Hongfa?
鸿发呢
No idea.
没看着
Take a seat.
坐吧 坐吧
Is this wine...
这酒是不是
Sit here.
坐这儿吧
From a restaurant?
酒楼的酒
Or the Station House?
还是我们单位的呀
I remember
我记得呀
the first time Yuansheng came,
远生第一次来我们家
he had 3 bowls of rice with veggies.
连吃了三碗菜泡饭
He ate too much.
把我心疼的呀
Made me so distressed.
那可是白花花的大米啊
It's my first time having it.
那是我第一次吃菜泡饭
Then, out of control.
确实吃得有点儿多
I made it again today
我今天又做了
with newly arrived rice
米是刚买的新米
and the veggies
这菜呢
Tianxiang and Qinqin
是天祥和勤芹一大早
bought back early in the morning.
去菜市场买的小青菜
Plenty more in the pot,
这锅里还有啊
enough for everyone.
管够
Thank you all.
谢谢你们
Let's bid
今天就算是给
Yuansheng
远生
farewell.
饯行吧
Sure.
好
Cheers!
来
All the best.
一路平安
Thanks.
谢谢
Best regards.
一路平安啊
Cool!
好嘞
This wine is good.
酒 酒不错啊
Try some.
尝尝
Minmin kept watching
这个是珉敏
over the stove to make this.
守着炉子一直熬出来的
She said it's your favourite.
她说你就喜欢吃这口
Eat it while it's hot.
趁热吃吧
You won't get this
离开上海
after leaving Shanghai.
就吃不到了
This is
远生
your second time leaving, right?
第二次要离开上海了吧
Yes.
对
After first visit to Shanghai,
远生第一次来上海
you became a police officer with us.
进了咱们四所当警察
On the second occasion,
第二次来上海
the Station was disbanded.
咱四所就解散了
But our friendship
不过咱这帮朋友的感情
has grown stronger.
越来越深了
Precisely.
是 是
I don't wanna leave
两进两出啊
this time more than last time.
一次比一次更舍不得
The rally
江海关集会
has really hit
对我们几个
us hard.
感触也挺大的
Hongfa, Tianxiang and I
我跟鸿发 还有天祥
have all decided
都已经想好了
to join the NSO
决定要去参加救国会
and contribute
为救亡运动
to the salvation movement.
也出一份儿力
Although I was a deserter before,
我虽然以前当过逃兵
I won't be this time around
但这次参加救国会
in joining the NSO.
我肯定不会再当逃兵了
Yuansheng,
远生
how about
要不你别走了
continuing to be with us?
留下跟我们一块儿啊
Even if I don't stay,
就算我不留下来
we'll
咱们
be on the same road.
以后也会走到一块儿的
That's right.
这话说得对
Agreed.
对
I propose
我提议啊
a toast
咱们四所的
to our Fourth Station.
一起喝一杯
Wait a minute.
等会儿 等会儿 等会儿
Before the toast,
喝一个可以
do you remember the slogan
还记得四所的精神
of the Fourth Station?
是什么吗
To uphold justice
匡扶正义
and protect the public.
保护百姓
Exactly.
对对对
Don't you think I forgot it?
你还考我们
Come on.
来
Yuansheng,
远生
do you know what the Director said
你第一次来四所
when you first appeared?
你知道所长说什么吗
"This boy
这小子
is marketable."
卖相真好
Did I say anything that cheesy?
我说过这么肉麻的话吗
Yeah.
得了
Don't act like you didn't.
你别以为我没听着啊
Something wrong with it?
听着了怎么着
He is a pretty boy indeed.
那人家卖相就是好是吧
Let's have a toast
为了卖相好
to the pretty boy!
干一个
Come on.
来
He is so pretty
卖相就是好
that he despised partnering
当初要跟我搭档
with me at that time.
还嫌弃我呢
Fortunately, I chose Dongbao
幸亏我当时抢冬宝
as my partner first...
抢得比较
Anyway,
那个
Yu,
小玉
Dongbao promised
冬宝之前答应
to start up a breakfast shop
跟你一块儿
with you.
开个早餐铺子
We've chosen a good place for the shop.
地方我们都选好了
It's just next door
就在我们家
to the Hongfa Restaurant.
鸿发酒楼隔壁
Yes.
对
When the shop opens,
到时候铺子开好了
we'll help you clean it up together.
我们一起帮你收拾
And we'll also look after
孩子出生了
the baby after his birth.
我们一起帮你照顾
You have so many friends here.
这么多人呢
We won't let you suffer.
不会让你们受苦的
Tell us if you need any help.
你有什么你就招呼
We're always on call.
随叫随到
Yes.
是是是
Thank you for all your care
谢谢大家这段时间
and support these days.
对我的照顾
Allow me to thank you
那我就以茶代酒
with tea toast.
敬大家一杯
You're so kind.
敬什么
We are a big family.
这都是自家人 自家人
Yuansheng,
小向
Do you have any news
陈浩那小子
about Chenhao?
有消息吗
I haven't
这小子
had any message from him.
真是一点儿消息也没有
I don't even know whether he's alive or not.
也不知道是生还是死
Director,
所长
you've known him
您和陈浩
for such a long time.
认识的时间最久
Then you must know
您应该知道
how lucky he is.
他是个好运气的人
I'm sure he can turn danger into safety.
他一定会化险为夷的
You're right.
这话说得对
Every time he's in trouble,
每次这臭小子惹祸啊
there's always someone who helped him out,
准有贵人帮着他
believe it or not.
你说这邪了门儿了都
Shall I propose a toast?
我提个酒
OK.
好嘞
Alright.
好啊
New Year is coming.
马上过年了啊
It's our
大冬天的
first gathering this winter.
咱们头一次聚在一起
I hope
那我希望啊
we could gather together
以后每年
every year thereafter.
咱们都聚
Shall we?
好不好
Sure!
好 好
I wish
我老左
all our comrades here,
祝在座的所有人
certainly as well as
当然了 也祝那个
the missing boy
不在这儿了
though I don't know where he is,
不知道干什么那臭小子
a safe and peaceful future
祝大家平平安安
and a healthy build.
长命百岁
Together!
好 来
Forever!
来
A safe and peace future
平平安安
and a healthy build.
长命百岁
Bottoms up!
都干了啊
The alcohol is so strong.
这酒有劲儿啊
And spicy.
辣辣辣
Sit down and have some food.
坐坐坐 吃饭吃饭吃饭
Even my ears taste the piquancy.
辣耳朵 辣耳朵
We've worked so hard this year.
我说啊 辛苦了啊
When the New Year comes,
等过年的时候
we should meet in my home
大家没事儿
whenever you're available.
都上我们家来吃饭
Good idea.
好
I'll show you my cooking skills.
回头我也露两手
When did you come back?
老乔什么时候回上海的
Not long ago.
刚刚
But I'll leave soon.
不过马上就走了
I got an order to return to Nanjing.
我接到任务要返回南京
I know you're waiting for his message.
我知道你在等他的消息
He asked me to hand it over
这个是他嘱咐我
to you in person.
亲手交给你的
Is he fine?
他还好吗
After I picked him up,
那天我接走他之后
I sent him to a hospital.
送他去了医院
He has been recovering these days.
这段时间都在康复
But doctor said
不过医生说
it's impossible
他肺里的弹片
to take out the debris left in his lungs.
确实没有办法取出来了
Mrs. Ji had told me.
我之前听季太太说过
Before I left him,
不过我走之前
he already had
他已经有一些
some gunshot sequelae
枪伤后遗症
slowly emerging.
在慢慢出现了
He's optimistic
他很乐观
and he faces
面对一切
all possible consequences
可能出现的后果
with a peaceful attitude.
也都很坦然
Will he return to Shanghai?
那他还会回上海吗
Not for now.
暂时不会了
Although we're far apart from each other,
虽然我们天各一方
I don't why
但不知道为什么
but I just
我总感觉
have a feeling that all of us are still together.
我们所有人并没有分开
No matter what happens in the future,
不管将来发生任何事
we shall be fearless
只要这支队伍不散
as long as we are part of the organization.
我们就无所畏惧
Just like seeing the sun
就像看见太阳
rise from the horizon.
从地平线上升起
Just like seeing the light
就像看见阳光
shine on the hazy plain.
照在晨雾笼罩的平原上
At this moment,
这一刻
I firmly believe
我突然觉得
this bright scenery
这种景色
is not far from us any more.
离我们不远了
Where are you going
你的新任务
for your new mission?
要去哪里呀
Guangzhou.
去广州
Apart from the mission,
除了任务
the organization worries that
组织也是考虑到
my identity would bring me danger
我的身份在上海和南京
If I stay in Shanghai or Nanjing.
会有危险
It's a protective move
去一个陌生的城市
to send me to an unknown city.
也是对我的保护吧
What about you?
你呢
Me?
我
I'll keep staying in Shanghai.
我会一直留在上海
Zijin Tailor Shop is no longer safe.
子衿裁缝铺用不了了
I want to take over Mrs. Ji's position.
我想接替季太太的位置
And I want to try
我也想试试
to establish
照相馆
the photo studio
能不能成为
into the next transfer station.
下一个中转点
These days
这段时间
I will learn from Ms. Shi
我会好好向石小姐学习
so that I can be competent for the job.
希望可以早一点胜任
In Guangzhou,
你去了广州
remember to take care of yourself.
要好好照顾自己啊
I will.
我会的
So
那
we say goodbye here.
我们就在这里说再见吧
Mind if I hug you?
拥抱一下吧
I don't know
下次
when we will meet
也不知道什么时候
next time.
才能再见了
At least,
那至少
we should shake our hands.
我们握个手嘛
I would be regretful
要是连手都不握
if we bade farewell
就这样告别的话
without shaking hands.
我会留有遗憾的
Alright.
那好吧
If you
要是
occasionally thought of us,
你偶尔想起我们
you could write to us.
可以写信回来
I will miss you.
我会想你的
I've chosen a path
我选择的
that I believe
是一条
it is correct.
自认为正确的道路
And I want to go
并且想要沿着它
straight down this road.
一直走下去
But I don't know
但我不知道
when I will reach the destination.
何时才能走到终点
I want to tell you to wait for me in Shanghai.
我想告诉你在上海等我
Or I want you to know
我也想说
I'll be waiting for you in Guangzhou.
我会在广州等你
But if we couldn't meet
但如果从今往后
each other ever since,
再也见不着面
I'd rather bear no hope.
我宁愿现在不留希望
I don't care even if I might be disappointed.
我不怕希望落空
I'll be waiting for you in Shanghai.
我会一直在上海等你的
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
Even though you're far away,
所思不远
my thoughts make you present as in the days gone by.
若为平生
I'll be waiting for you in Shanghai.
我在上海等你
"Don't feel sad because of departure,"
莫道秋江离别难
"the destination will be a hopeful future."
舟船明日是长安
A few months is not that long,
几个月的时间并不算长
but fairly enough to change everything.
但足以改变太多
Xiang Yuansheng, don't be impulsive.
向远生 你那么冲干吗
Xiang Yuansheng,
向远生
come out!
出来
You've caused us a lot of trouble.
你这不又给咱添麻烦吗
You are not qualified.
你有资格吗
They said you join the Communist Party.
他们说您加入了共产党
I don't care who is my partner
和谁搭档无所谓
because I don't need
我没有想过在这里
a partner here.
需要搭档
It smells good.
闻起来还挺香的
Yuansheng.
远生
It is Yuansheng, indeed.
真是远生
I should call you officer Xiang instead.
还是叫向警官吧
So weird.
别扭
I remember when I first came to Shanghai,
记得我第一次来上海
I walked
走过的
on the same street.
也是这条街
At that time,
当时的我
I firmly believed
还坚定地认为
that I was walking
自己正走在一条
on an absolutely correct road.
无比正确的道路上
Until
直到
I met them.
我遇到了他们
It's a police officer‘s duty to fight for justice,
当警察是为了匡扶正义
and to protect the public.
保护百姓
It just like
这就像
a doctor can't choose his patients,
医生不能选择病人
and a soldier can't select a battlefield.
军人不能选择战场
I always believe
我一直觉得
it's the same to a police officer.
警察也是一样
To let China rise up
中华崛起
and to create a prosperous and peaceful country.
国泰民安
Until now,
到今天
my ideals remain the same.
我的理想依然如此
Even in the most emergency situation,
就是在最慌张的时候
Get on the car.
快上车
they still made
她们也做出了
the best decision.
最正确的决定
You are such a good
你这警察呀
and competent policeman.
当得挺好
I just found
我才发现
I am
我其实
actually so unfamiliar
对脚下的这片土地
with my home country
知之甚少
She's not only a police officer,
她不光是个警员
she is just a girl!
她还是个女孩子
What about you?
你们呢
And the senior?
老的呢
What about your promise to Luo Minmin?
骆珉敏的承诺呢
What about your promise to the Fourth Station?
四所的承诺呢
I pulled
那颗扣子
the button down
是我从凶手身上
from the assailant.
拽下来的
Does it help?
它有没有用
Don't worry.
放心
It helps.
扣子有用
It must be useful.
一定会有用的
I want my resignation letter back.
我来要回我的辞呈
Don't move!
不许动 别动 别动
It's them who changed my mind
是他们让我蜕变
and make me grow up.
让我成长
I, Luo Minmin request to return to the crew
警员骆珉敏请求归队
Enjoy the cooperation.
合作愉快
Hope everything is ducky.
一切顺利
Some strength is beyond ability.
有的强大与能力无关
This never
这是之前
occurred to me before.
我从来没有想过的
Officer Xiang.
向警官
I'm married.
我结婚了
You're married?
你结婚了
He wants to open
他就想给小玉
a breakfast shop for Yu,
开个早餐铺子
and has a child of them.
将来再生个一儿半女
It will be a wonderful life.
那小日子多美
Dongbao doesn't need your money.
冬宝是缺你这点儿钱吗
What are you on guard against?
你在提防什么
Are you on guard against me?
是在提防我吗
Somebody help!
来人啊
People are not actually that insignificant.
人其实也没有那么渺小
Yes.
对
We are much stronger
我们比自己想象的
than we thought.
要强大
Do you really want to break your life plan
你真的要因为一个答案
just for a so-called answer?
打乱自己的人生规划吗
I must know the truth.
我必须知道真相
You're not the only one who pursues the truth.
要查也不是你一个人查
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
How do you want me to understand you?
你让我怎么理解
Do you want to be
难道你想做
a traitor and collaborator to our country?
日本人的汉奸和走狗吗
It's your family's fault,
那也是你的家庭
not yours.
不是你
It's never too late
人只要选择对了方向
to choose the right path.
任何时间都不晚
Take it.
拿着
Punctuality.
把握好时刻
The reason why
回顾这样一些
I look back on these moments
群星闪耀的时刻
is because they
是因为它们
were like shooting stars,
宛如星辰一般
sparkling and shining.
永远散射着光辉
They light up
普照着
the fading darkness.
终将消失的黑夜
The greatest fortune in life
人生最大的幸运
is to set up life purpose
莫过于在年富力强时
at a strong and young age.
发现了自己的人生使命
It's a hardest farewell
此次一别
when we left each other,
虽然心有不舍
but fortunately,
但值得庆幸的是
I'm no longer
我的内心
confused about my direction.
已然有了方向
Qin,
勤芹
let me call a rickshaw for you.
爸给你叫个黄包车吧
No thanks dad.
不用了 爸
I run faster than a rickshaw.
我跑着比黄包车快
Come on!
加油啊
Don't worry.
放心吧
I will pass the exam!
肯定金榜题名
Watch out!
看车
Stay still.
保持啊
Three, two, one.
三二一
Ms. Shi,
石小姐
you can pick up the photo
后天就可以过来
the day after tomorrow.
取照片了
OK.
好
Does your sister have an exam today?
你妹妹是今天考试对吗
Yes.
对
She applied for the entry to Medical University.
她报了医科大学
She always did well in the study.
她成绩一向很好
I believe she will be admitted.
我相信她会考上的
My brother is also a doctor.
我大哥也是医生
It's a good profession.
医生是个好职业
I would congratulate her in advance.
那就提前祝贺她了
Thank you.
谢谢
Jianshi is in Shanghai.
老乔来上海了
He wants to meet you
他说想跟你见面
at the same place
就在老地方见面
Luo Minmin,
骆珉敏同志
you need to practice
你也应该好好练一下
your facial expression management more.
你的表情管理了
Yes, madam.
收到
Take it easy.
知道了
Hello, is anyone there?
你好 有人吗
Yes.
这边
Do you want to take photos?
你们是过来拍照的吗
Yes,
对
we want to take a set of couple photos.
我们想拍一组情侣照片
OK.
好
This way please.
这边请
Goodbye Ms. Shi.
石小姐 慢走啊
You want to take some couple photos.
你们想拍一组情侣照
Yes.
对
Do you like poems?
你喜欢读诗吗
I only read
只读过
'The Train' of Taranci.
塔朗吉的《火车》
Do you know what's
那你知道车头上
the sentence on the locomotive?
写的是什么吗
Bridges are strong,
愿你桥都坚固
tunnel light.
隧道都光明
Long time no see.
好久不见